# **PASCAL JARDIN**

858-472-9511 | pjardin@me.com | Poway, CA 92064 www.github.com/pjardin | www.pascaljardin.com | www.linkedin.com/in/PascalJardin/

### **SUMMARY AND KEY SKILLS**

Collaborative, motivated, and solution-driven Computer Scientist with successful experience working in remote, distributed, global, and fast-paced environments. A second-generation computer scientist with comprehensive experience in research and development. Excited to utilize current technical knowledge and quick learning mindset to create a significant impact. Demonstrated strong communication skills and reputed as an exceptional problem solver, organizer and advocate, working with teams toward shared goals and objectives.

#### **TECHNOLOGIES**

Google Drive (Docs, Sheets, Slides), Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint), Dropbox, Zoom, Slack, Skype, JIRA, HomeBase, Jenkins, Postman, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Java, Java 16, C++, OOP, C, C#, Objective-C, Swift, Android, iOS, GitHub, Git, SQL, MySQL, PSQL, Computer Vision, Augmented Reality (AR), Virtual Reality (VR), Open CV, dlib, bash, Linux, command line, VIM, APIs, AWS Lambda, AWS DynamoDB, Blender, 3d Animation, 3D Graphics, Unity, Unreal Engine, React, Spring Framework, Node.js, jQuery, Visual Studio, Android Studio, XCode, Eclipse, Postman, Python, Git, SQL, RabbitMQ, MySQL, Mongo, Visual Studio, Linux OS, Windows OS, Mac OS

### **EDUCATION AND RELEVANT COURSEWORK**

Bachelor of Science (BS) | Computer Science, California State University San Marcos California

5/2020

Graduated with Magna Cum Laude, high honors, GPA 3.713

Machine Learning Systems | Introduction to Mobile Programming | Game Programming

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Scientist | Lead Front End Developer | Full Time | Citizen Science for Navy

12/2020 - Present

NIWC, Point Loma, CA

Pascal Jardin, Poway, CA

- Lead front end developer.
- Automated testing with Jenkins.
- Mongo, RabbitMQ database management.
- Launching and managing VM, virtual machines, with AWS.

# Owner | Instructor | Fully Remote | Part Time | Virtual, Home-Based Office, Poway, California

10/2020 - Present

- Successful business owner of Pascal Jardin Outschool classes.
- Teaching ages 10 to 15 years old 3d animation, VFX, 3d graphics, 2d animation, and Blender.
- Highest rated Blender Teacher on https://outschool.com
- https://outschool.com/classes/intro-to-blender-and-3d-animation-part-1-92FuKfyZ#usWvMRL01i

# Instructor | Fully Remote | Part Time | Virtual, Home-Based Office, Poway, California

7/2020 - 11/2020

Delaware STEAM Academy, Newark, DE

Teaching Python and JavaScript classes ages 8 to 16 years old.

## Blender Artist | Fully Remote | Internship | Virtual, Home-Based Office, Poway, California

6/2020 - 8/2020

Kana's Island, Las Angeles, CA

- Internship under the Disney Imagineer Mark Page
- Created demo game "Kana's Cookie run" using the Unreal.
- Created entire teaser <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2vS6z80qOUY">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2vS6z80qOUY</a>
- Created figurines https://skfb.ly/6U9qp, https://skfb.ly/6U99O
- Lighting, rigging, modeling, animation, sound and VFX

# Front End Developer | Fully Remote | 6 Week Contract | Home-Based Office, Poway, California

5/2020 - 6/2020

- Work on a 5-member team as a Front End Developer developing a react portal for users in shipping items
  - Execute application development within very tight time constraints within a one week, sprint period
  - Collaborate and complete back end development work with odoo.sh as needed due to the strict deadlines
  - Process tickets logged through JIRA while communicating with team members regularly through Slack and logging in with HomeBase
  - Successfully doubled the website loading speed and tripled the performance by storing data into a cache

### AWS developer | Full Stack Engineer | Blender Artist | Freelancer | Fully Remote

5/2020 - 6/2020

LadyJustice.us, San Marcos, CA

- Designed, developed, and hosted <a href="https://ladyjustice.us">https://ladyjustice.us</a>.
- Hosted on AWS through rout 53 and s3 bucket.
- Secured website using AWS cloud front
- Created multiple videos using Blender, can be found on site.

Instructor/Teacher 1/2020 – 5/2020

The Coder School, San Diego, CA

- Develop individualized and targeted curriculums for each student to aide them in achieving coding education goals
- Instruct, mentor, and coach students on coding languages as a "Coder Coach", Python, Java, HTML, and JavaScript, as well as coding tools such as Blender and Unity

### Full Stack Engineer | Fully Remote | Virtual, Home-Based Office, Poway, California Graffiti Artist, Stockholm, Sweden

11/2018 - 01/2019

- Partnered with professional graffiti artist and owner of MindGem Graphics on developing and launching internet/social media presence through creation of http://graffiticreator.net utilizing iMessage Graffiti creator app, https://apps.apple.com/us/app/graffiti-creator-stickers/id1449321346?ls=1
- Created a web app using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery and XCode and swift

# Research and Development Engineer | Part Time | Flexible Schedule

08/2014 - 01/2020

Jardin Labs, Poway, CA

- Designed and created a Patent web scrapper using Python to search/scrap all patents and store in a database for a patent firm; resulting in the patent firm's ability to search for copyright infringements
- Crafted front end and back end design development for PopTagz, an augmented reality graffiti app allowing the
  user to tag in a virtual reality space; Utilized web apps and Swift to gather user GPS locations and pulled content
  from an AWS sever, apps.apple.com/us/app/poptagz/id1265471660?ls=1
- Participated in the Shielded research project to develop VR EEG headset for network security; wrote Unity code
  in C# to display content to users and implemented sockets between open BCI, allowing for brain data and
  raspberry pi data to be sent to Amazon servers for data processing
- Wrote Python socket code connecting "the frame" of a project to an Amazon s3 bucket utilized in the Forget Me
   Not research project focused on stimulating memory abilities